<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Risk | Data Pokémon 🍱</title>
    <link>/tag/risk/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/risk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Risk</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hufcd75c8c36f769d2edb1fe6215a7f155_163455_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Risk</title>
      <link>/tag/risk/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparative analysis of risk control effect of three major cities in Yorkshire under covid-19</title>
      <link>/project/risk_control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/risk_control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;plot1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the public health crisis of global pneumonia in 2020, three tasks are carried out: to analyze the epidemic situation and control situation in Leeds York Sheffield by time series analysis, and to explore the management structure problems reflected in the large-scale public health and safety problems, by analyzing the overall and local case growth in the UK. Through the government&amp;rsquo;s public opinion survey report, the demand of merchants and the results of the government&amp;rsquo;s subsidy and assistance are clarified,finding the gap between plan and implementation. To explore the effectiveness of the measures and implementation formulated by the government, and compare the gap between the two. By comparing the expected effect of the annual financial plan and risk planning with the actual situation, the relationship between the control and management effect of the three local epidemic situation and the above two is compared. Finally, it evaluates whether financial budget can be effectively used in risk assessment, and examines the decision-making and bias of local governments in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop an open dashboard for local government based on spending data</title>
      <link>/project/council_spending/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/council_spending/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;plot1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, with the increasing development of open data as well as public’s awareness of performance evaluation for local governments to see whether governments are doing their jobs. In this way, local governments have to satisfy the increasing needs from the public and make full use of the open data. Thus, this paper is aiming to provide a way for local governments to use open government data to develop open data driven KPI to evaluate their performance and use visualization to monitor their performance and facilitate participations of the public. Based on this, the spending data of Leeds Council is used to mine the possible patterns within the data through cluster analysis and dashboard is used to manage the performance in the visual way. In this case, spending is defined as the open KPI to evaluate the performance of Leeds Council and it is found that there are priorities of spending which can be compared with operational goals to determine whether Leeds government has good performance. Finally, it is suggested that not only local governments but also business corporations can utilize the open data to create more values and support their decisions making.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
