<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wenxin Zhong | Data Pokémon 🍱</title>
    <link>/author/wenxin-zhong/</link>
      <atom:link href="/author/wenxin-zhong/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Wenxin Zhong</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hufcd75c8c36f769d2edb1fe6215a7f155_163455_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Wenxin Zhong</title>
      <link>/author/wenxin-zhong/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determine the cause factors of software publishing start-ups survival in the UK</title>
      <link>/project/startup_-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/startup_-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project analyses the survival situation of 9,067 software publishing companies registered in the UK in 2014 within five years after their establishment. First, we analyse what start-ups and software publishing companies are, what are their characteristics, motivations, current and common survival issues, and factors that may affect survival. Then, we apply the K-NN algorithm, support vector machine and decision tree model to train and optimise these models, and then test and predict classification. The decision tree model classified UK software publishing start-ups with turnover per employee of more than 88,000 GBP and a start-up team of more than three and less than five as those that could successfully survive the initial stage. We have the basic data of these start-ups in the FAME database, and the K-NN algorithm and support vector machine can predict the survival of these start-ups with over 90% accuracy based on their characteristic data. However, both models also have the problem of misjudging a company that fails to survive as a successful one, which brings losses to entrepreneurs or investors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
